Siarhei Thor | Msc. Arch. Eng.

Data Science | Data Analysis | Business Intelligence

SUMMARY

Siarhei is a proactive Data Scientist specialised in NLP and predictive modelling. He has comprehensive knowledge in Python, R, SQL, and advanced machine learning frameworks, including TensorFlow and LangChain. Siarhei has successfully developed predictive models to optimise athletic performance and has innovated data-to-text response features to enhance data analysis and communication. He is adept at using AI to deliver business value and enhance operational efficiency. Whether working as part of a team or independently, Siarhei consistently drives projects to successful completion.

SKILLS

The following is a summary of my day-to-day skillset and an overview of the most used programming languages, frameworks, and packages:

- Data Collection & Preparation: **SQL.**
- Statistical Modeling / Testing: R, Python (SciPy, statsmodels).
- Data Analysis, Feature Engineering, Visualisation: Python (Pandas, Polars, Seaborn, Plotly), R (dplyr, ggplot2).
- Machine / Deep Learning Frameworks and Algorithms: Scikit-Learn,
 TensorFlow, LangChain, OpenCV, XGBoost, LightGBM.
- Data Engineering, Cloud and Deployment: Linux, Docker, Dokku, GCP.
- Version Control & Collaborations: GIT.
- BI Data Visualization: Tableau.

EXPERIENCE

Quevita AG, Olten - Data Scientist, MLOps

January 2024 - now

Focused on enhancing athletic performance through advanced AI. I build predictive models, targeting key metrics to optimise and enhance the training process.

- Quantitative analysis of athletes' performance.
- Developed a predictive model for athletes' 10 km performance based on training data.

Perspetivo AB, Stockholm - Data Scientist

September 2023 - Januari 2024 (100%), January 2024 - April 2024 (40%)

Responsible for creating data-driven products and ensuring data quality across data pipelines and AI tools integration.

- Developed 'Ask Data' feature, converting tabular data to text responses in chat format (NLP).
- Maintained data pipelines for a large-scale survey database.
- Conceptualised and developed the first three MVP versions of a 'Dashboard as a Service' product.

STHLM22, Stockholm - Consultant, AI Strategy and Digitalization

September 2021 - September 2023

Consulted on AI implementation and digital strategies, enhancing operational efficiency and data utilisation for real estate and architectural firms.

Highlighted consultancy and freelance projects:

- Consulted on AI implementation strategies, enhancing data utilisation and operational efficiency for clients in real estate and architecture.
- Developed innovative applications, including a GPT-3.5 powered AI chatbot for regulatory compliance and a Stable Diffusion/ControlNet integrated app for architectural design.

Semren & Månsson, Stockholm; Sweco, Göteborg; Cie, Amsterdam – (Senior) Architect, Parametric design, Digital Strategy

January 2015 - October 2021

Worked as an building architect on several prestigious projects in Amsterdam, Göteborg and Stockholm utilising a background in programming to create complex computational design solutions. Leveraged technical knowledge in BIM to optimise delivery pipelines in various projects, achieving resource optimization and faster delivery times.

- Successfully led diverse international teams of up to 20 members, delivering building projects up to 5 million sq. m.
- Enhanced project delivery speed by 50% through strategic integration of AI and ML tools.
- Developed educational programs for junior architects on computational design and AI application.

EDUCATION

MSc, Architectural Engineering — TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY DELFT, The Netherlands

September 2009 - June 2014, Delft

Specialised in Architectural Engineering and Technology, focusing on sustainable and efficient building practices within the constraints of limited global resources. Engaged deeply with cutting-edge developments in building technology, installation technology, and digital design methodologies. Contributed to research on new design and manufacturing methods aimed at enhancing the sustainability of new and existing buildings. Gained comprehensive skills in architectural informatics (coding) and design, equipped to address aesthetic, comfort, and environmental health challenges in the built environment.

EXTRACURRICULAR EDUCATION

Higher Vocational Education Program, Data Science — EC (IT - school), Online / Stockholm

August 2023 - June 2024, Stockholm

This full-time Data Science program at EC Education focuses on equipping students with key skills in data collection, processing, and analysis. It combines practical programming in SQL, R, and Python with advanced training in statistics and machine learning to enable strategic, data-driven decision making.

ONLINE COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS

- Google Advanced Data Analytics, Coursera, Jan-Jun 2023
- Deep Learning Specialization, Deeplearning.ai, Dec 2022-Apr 2023
- Machine Learning Specialization, Deeplearning.ai, Sep-Dec 2022
- LLM Finetuning and Prompt Engineering, Deeplearning.ai, Sep 2023
- IBM Data Science Specialization, Coursera, Sep-Dec 2022

HOBBIFS

Orientering, Trail Running, Photography.

PROFILES

https://www.linkedin.com/in/siarhei-thor/

https://github.com/SiarheiThor